Farzin Jabbary

Web Developer
647-675-2131
farzin.jabbary@gmail.com
Toronto, ON
github.com/fjabbary

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduated with Master's degree in Engineering from Southern Illinois University Carbondale. Self-motivated, punctual, fast learner, having good communication skills, and works well with others. Good interaction with developers, and team members to coordinated job tasks and strong commitment to work. Proficient in Front-end and backend Web Applications development using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, JavaScript, JQuery, Reactjs/Redux, AJAX, JSON, RESTFUL API, Nodejs, express, and MongoDB. Experienced working in an agile environment and also project management tools such as JIRA and Trello.

EDUCATION

Full-time full stack web developing Diploma BrainStation, Toronto, ON 01/2019-04/2019

Master of Science in Engineering Southern Illinois University Carbondale 2012-2014

TECHNICAL PROFECIENCY

Front-end Web Technologies	HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SASS, BEM, Flexbox, Responsive web design, JavaScript, Typescript, JQuery, AJAX, JSON, Reactjs, Single Page Application (SPA)
Back-end Web Technologies	Nodejs, express, MongoDB, RESTFUL API
Other Tools	Gulpjs, MS Office, Firebug, Chrome Developers Tool, Git, Github, Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Agile Methodology, JIRA, NPM

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer, Salefish Software, Vaughan, ON

08/2019-10/2019

- Develop websites and other web applications using Photoshop files provided by the in-house Design team
- Responsible for doing the HTML, JavaScript, React and CSS work to convert Photoshop prototypes into a responsive working website

Full-time Trainee for Full-stack Web Development - Bootcamp, BrainStation, Toronto, ON 01/2019-04/2019

- Design and development of applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, SASS, npm, Nodejs, express, MySQL
- Worked on Responsive design
- Developed the various pages and its architecture in accordance to UI Specs.

- Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and designing issues with JavaScript and React
- Worked with React charts for the construction of different charts in the application
- Integrated the front end using the JSON data from the backend.
- Worked with different distributed teams as a part of the project and integrated the front end with the JSON data from the api calls

Front end Web Developer, TakroSystem, Tabriz, Iran

08/2017-01/2019

- Participated in online training provided by a company
- Working as a front end developer
- Web design and development, application development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages in the application using HTML5, CSS3, JQuery
- Responsible for design and development of the web pages from mock-ups.
- Developed the various pages and its architecture in accordance to UI Specs.

PLC Programmer and Technician, Caterpillar company, San Diego, CA

08/2014-08/2017

- Provide technical advice to customers with the company products and operation of equipment
- Troubleshooting of PLC and input/output modules using communication tools